Papish, Nancy; Papers apap144
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- James Bay Activism Files, 1963; 1987; 1990-1994; Undated; 2; 0.6 cubic ft.
  Also found in this series is information on the 1990 Odeyak voyage, in which Cree and Inuit community members traveled from their homes to New York City in a boat that was a cross between a kayak and a canoe. The Odeyak passengers received food and housing from activists along their route, and Papish helped arrange accommodations for them in the Albany area. In 1994, New York activists staged a recreation of the Odeyak trip between Albany and New York City.
  The items in folders marked "News Clippings, Press Releases, and Mailings" were originally housed in a large binder. The archivist maintained the original order of materials within the binder.
  - Ban the Dam Bulletin, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 1)
  - Bread and Puppet Theatre, 1992 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 2)
  - "Briefing Memorandum Concerning the 800 and 400 MW Seasonal Diversity Contract...", 1993 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 3)
  - Brochures and Fliers, 1993; Undated (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 5)
  - Discussion Questions, 1990 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 6)
  - Fact Sheets, Undated (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 7)
  - For No One Knows Waswonipi, Miller, Hugo, Undated (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 8)
  - Grand Council of the Crees, 1989-1991 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 9)
  - Grande Baleine Hydroelectric Project, Canadian Minister of the Environment Press Release, 1991 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 10)
  - Great Whale River, 1994; Undated (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 11)
  - Gwich'in Steering Committee, 1991 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 12)
  - Hinchey Bill, 1996 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 13)
  - Hoyt Bill, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 14)
  - Innu Nation, 1990-1992 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 15)
  - Innu Nation, Lower Churchill Dam Alert and Update, 1991 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 16)
  - International Conference to Save James Bay, 1994 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 17)
  - James Bay Action Network, 1991; Undated (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 18)
  - James Bay Defense Coalition, 1990; 1993 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 19)
  - "James Bay Destruction Is Go", Albany Peace and Energy Council, Article, 1993 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 20)
  - James Bay and Northern Waters Network, Meeting Announcement, 1998 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 21)
  - Leichter, Senator Franz, Testimony, 1994 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 22)
  - Lessons, Undated (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 23)
  - Letter to Mario Cuomo from Todd Van Schaick, 1991 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 24)
  - Letters to Political Leaders from Schoharie Students, 1991 (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 25)
  - Magazine Articles, 1963; 1987; 1990-1992; Undated (Box 1 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 26)
  - Magazine Articles, 1992; Undated (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 1)
  - The Nation, 1993 December 1 (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 2)
  - New York James Bay Activist Meetings, 1991 (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 3)
  - New York James Bay Network, 1992-1994 (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 4)
  - New York Power Authority Letter, 1990 (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 5)
  - New York State Legislature Briefing Paper, 1991 (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 6)
  - New York State United Teachers, Resolution Opposing James Bay II, Undated (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 7)
  - News Clippings, 1990-1993 (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 8-9)
  - News Clippings, Press Releases, and Mailings, 1991 (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 10)
  - News Clippings, Press Releases, and Mailings, 1991-1992 (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 11-13)
  - Northeast Indian Quarterly Akwe:kon Journal, Readings on James Bay, 1991 (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 14)
  - Northeast Regional James Bay Action Conference, 1991 (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 15)
  - Notes, 1992-1994; Undated (Box 2 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 16)
  - Odeyak Trip, 1990 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 1)
  - Odeyak Trip, 1994 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 2)
  - P.R.O.T.E.C.T., 1990-1993; Undated (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 3)
  - P.R.O.T.E.C.T., James Bay Updates, 1992-1994 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 4)
  - Petition to Senator Moynihan, Blank, ca. 1991 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 5)
  - Political Cartoons, 1990-1991 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 6)
  - Press Release, Governor's Office, 1991 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 7)
  - Quebec Hydropower Bill, New York State Assembly Briefing Paper, 1990 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 8)
  - "Quebec Opts for Hydroelectricity", Quebec Economique International Special Report, 1991 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 9)
  - Sierra Club, James Bay and Northern Quebec Task Force, 1990-1991 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 10)
  - Solidarity Committee of the Capital District, James Bay Flier, Undated (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 11)
  - Speakers Bureau, 1993; Undated (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 12)
  - Statistics, ca. 1991 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 13)
  - Student Environmental Action Coalition, 1992 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 14)
  - Team No Phase II, 1992 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 15)
  - U.S. Electricity Trade with Canada and Mexico, Energy Information Administration, 1992 (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 16)
  - Underwriters of Hydro-Quebec's U.S. Debentures, List, Undated (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 17)
  - "Why Canadian Hydropower for New York?" New York Power Authority, Undated (Box 3 (2-James Bay Activism Files), Folder 18)
- Environmental Education Files, 1970-1986; Undated; 3; 0.6 cubic ft.
  This series contains guides, handouts, worksheets, and other materials related to environmental education. It is unclear how Papish used these materials. The series consists largely of published guides for Project Learning Tree and Project WILD, education programs developed by the Western Regional Environmental Council. Also included are three photocopied excerpts from books on environmental education.
  - Brochures - "Plants that Poison", and Finding Marine Information in Libraries, 1976; Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 1)
  - Catholic News: Features on Educational Sails, 1971 (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 2)
  - "Chemical and Physical Aspects of Water Pollution", Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 3)
    Photocopied Book Chapter, Unknown Author.
  - Clearwater First Worksheets, Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 4)
  - Cultural Ecology of the Mohawk Valley: Workshop at Whitesboro High School, 1977 (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 5)
  - Education Department Update, Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 6)
  - Environmental Educator and Director Job Descriptions, Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 7)
  - "Floating Classroom" Article, Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 8)
  - Gallon-Jar Marine Aquaria, Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 9)
  - Handouts: List of Fish Species Found in the Hudson River, Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 10)
  - Handouts: Wood as Fuel, Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 11)
  - Hudson River Community Education Program Brochure, 1984 (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 12)
  - Hudson River Studies Lesson Packet I, 1985 (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 13)
  - Hudson River Studies Lesson Packet II, 1986 (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 14)
  - "Investigating Science in the Swimming Pool and Ocean", Norman D. Anderson, Undated; photocopy (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 15)
  - Lesson Plans: Teaching Stations Aboard Clearwater, Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 16)
  - "Life in Lakes and Ponds", Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 17)
    Photocopied Book Chapter, no author.
  - Project Learning Tree, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 18)
  - Project Learning Tree Branch, 1985 Winter (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 19)
  - Project Learning Tree, Manuals, Samples, Undated (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 20)
  - Project Learning Tree, Supplementary Activity Guide for Grades K-6, 1977 (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 21)
  - Project Learning Tree, Supplementary Activity Guide for Grades 7-12, 1977 (Box 1 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 22)
  - Project WILD, 1984-1985; Undated (Box 2 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 1)
  - Project WILD, Secondary Activity Guide, 1985 (Box 2 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 2)
  - Return a Gift to Wildlife Program, Workshops, Undated (Box 2 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 3)
  - Sailing Register, 1979 July-1979 August (Box 2 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 4)
  - "Science World" by Scholastic Magazine, 1970 (Box 2 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 5)
  - Student Worksheets, Undated (Box 2 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 6)
  - Teacher's Guide -- "Clearwater: A Dream for a River", Undated (Box 2 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 7)
  - Water Quality Testing Devices, Undated (Box 2 (3-Environmental Education Files), Folder 8)
- Subject Files, 1968-1994; Undated; 4; 2.6 cubic ft.
  Files on miscellaneous environmental issues and non-environmental topics, including (but certainly not limited to) anti-nuclear activity, Hudson River conservation, and outdoor recreation. There are files on several specific environmental organizations such as Environmental Clearinghouse of Schenectady and the Hudson River Waterway Association. Also included are three folders of plates with historical images of Albany streets. These images came from an unidentified publication, and their relationship to other items in the collection is uncertain. Finally, there are U.S. Geological Survey maps (saved from the woodshed of the ferry sloop Woody Guthrie) which are housed with the oversized materials. (Series 8.).
  - Acid Rain Booklets, 1982; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - "The Adirondack: The Land Nobody Knows" Brochure, 1980 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Albany Institute of History and Art Brochure, Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Albany Street Scenes, Plates, ca. 1880-1950 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4-6)
  - Albany International Center: Netherlands Flotilla Crew, 1976 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Albany League of Arts, 1978-1979; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Annual Report of Assembly Standing Committee on Environmental Conservation, 1977 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Anti-Nuclear Material, 1979; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Applications: Department of the Army Permits for Activities in Waterways, 1974 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Assorted Environmental Groups, 1979; 1987; 1989; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Bay/Estuary Coalition Directory, 1983 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Bioregional Conference, Omega Institute, 1984; 1986 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Brochures: General Assortment (Boat Launching, NYS Bike Trails, etc), Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Brochures: General Assortment (Environmental Rights, Five Rivers, etc), Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Canals: New York State, 1973; Undated (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Canals: New York State Recreation Development Program, 1973; 1975 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Capital District Humanities Program, Undated (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Capital District Regional Planning Commission Data, 1979 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Center for Environmental Options, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Center for the Hudson River Valley, ca. 1977 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Chesapeake Bay Initiative -- National Audubon Society, 1984 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Coastal Zone Management, 1987; 1989; Undated (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Coastal Zone Management in the Capital District -- Phase 1, 1976 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Coastal Zone Management in the Capital District -- Phase 2, 1977 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Commoner, Barry: Biologist, 1976-1977; Undated (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Del-Aware Unlimited, Inc. -- Projects, 1982-1983; Undated (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Dredging Notices (Hudson River): U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, 1982-1985 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Eastfield Village Historic Preservation and American Trades Workshops, 1982 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - "Ecological Studies of the Hudson River in the Vicinity of Lloyd, NY: 1973-1974", Vol.1, Chapters 1-3, 1975 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - "Ecological Studies of the Hudson River in the Vicinity of Lloyd, NY: 1973-1974", Vol.1, Appendices A-B, 1975 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - "Ecological Studies of the Hudson River in the Vicinity of Lloyd, NY: 1973-1974", Vol.2, Appendices C-F, 1975 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - "Ecological Studies of the Hudson River in the Vicinity of Lloyd, NY: 1973-1974", Vol.2, Appendices G-I, 1975 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Empire State Regatta Program, 1985 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Environment: New York State, 1968-1984 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Environmental Brochures/Booklets -- General, 1976-1982; Undated (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Environmental Clearinghouse of Schenectady: Brochures and Subscription Information, Undated (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Environmental Clearinghouse of Schenectady: Newsletter, 1976 March-1977 November (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Environmental Planning Lobby: Brochures, Voter's Guide, and Miscellaneous, ca. 1976-1985 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Environmental Planning Lobby: Newsletters, 1976 July-1979 December (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Environmental Standard Review Plan: Intro.-4.1, 1977 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Environmental Standard Review Plan: Section 4.3-End, 1977 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Five-Year Water Quality Management Program: EPA and NYS ENCON, 1978-1983 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - General Motors (Massena, NY) Superfund Cleanup -- EPA Press Release, 1992 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Gerber, Morris, 1976; Undated (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Girl Scouts of America, Undated (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Girl Scouts: "The Gift of Water" Project, ca. 1982 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Girl Scouts of America: Junior Girl SCout Handbook, 1986 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Girl Scouts of America: Scout Badges and Signs, 1980 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - "Green Vote Handbook: Environmentalists and Electoral Politics", 1982 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Great Hudson River Tour Brochure, 1980 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Greenpeace, Undated (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Greenworking, 1991 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Hemp, 1991 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Historical Interests and Preservation, 1981; 1984; Undated (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Hudson Estuary Reinhabitation, Undated (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Hudson-Mohawk Industrial Gateway, 1981; Undated (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Hudson River Federal Channel Maintenance Dredging -- Draft Impact Statement/10-year Plan, Intro.-Appendix D, 1981 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Hudson River Federal Channel Maintenance Dredging -- Draft Impact Statement/10-year Plan, Appendix E-End, 1981 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Hudson River Federal Channel Maintenance Dredging -- Vol. 1, 1983 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Hudson River Federal Channel Maintenance Dredging -- Vol. 2, Appendices A-J, 1983 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Hudson River Federal Channel Maintenance Dredging -- Vol. 2, Appendices K-M, 1983 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Hudson River Fishery Management Program Study, 1980 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Hudson River -- General, 1982; 1989; 1991-1994; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Hudson River Waterway Association, 1993; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Institute for Social Ecology, 1985 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Labor Education Day, 1977 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Living River Journey, 1993 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Mears, Deb, Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Mears, Deb -- New York State History Course Notes and Exams, 1983 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Mohawk-Hudson Water Quality 208 Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Nature Conservancy, 1978; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - New Netherland Project -- New York State Library, Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - New York Public Interest Research Group: Superfund and Community Right-to-Know Bill, 1985; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - New York State Assembly Districts, 1984 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - New York State Coastal Management Handbook, 1978 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - New York State Dept. of Environmental Conservation, 1979-1985 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - New York State Environmental Congress Brochure, 1992 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - New York State Environmental Conservation Directory, 1983 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - New York State/EPA Agreement -- Water Quality Management, 1978 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - New York State Hazardous Waste Treatment Facilities Task Force -- Status Report/Final Draft, 1985 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - New York State History Maps and Timeline, Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - New York State Outdoor Guides Association, 1984; 1986; Undated (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - New York Statewide Comprehensive Recreation Plan Manual, 1972 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Newsletters: Assorted Organizations, 1976-1978; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Newsletter: Feeder Canal Towline, 1990 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - "Old Sailing Days on the Hudson": Maritime Drawings of John D. Woodward, ca. 1976 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Organization for Action for the Riverfront (Schenectady) -- Troy Conservationist Article, 1986 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Outdoor Recreation, 1985; 1990-1992; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - PCB Brochures, 1981 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - "People and Toxics": NYS Public Participation Pilot Project, Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Performing Arts Material, 1971-1979; 1982-1984; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
    (includes Alvin Ailey, Lake George Opera).
  - Polluting the Hudson: Business as Usual (Oct. 1981-June 1984), 1985 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Polluting the Hudson: A Gentleman's Agreement (Synopsis), ca. 1983 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Polluting the Hudson: A Gentleman's Agreement (Report for Oct. 1979-Sept. 1981), 1983 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Port of Albany 50th Anniversary, 1982 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - POW WOWs -- New England Native Americans, 1992-1993 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Pumpkin Happy Cookbook, 1976 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Real Estate -- Environmentally Friendly Options, 1979; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Recommendations for Environmental Legislation, 1985 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Return a Gift to Wildlife Guide, 1986; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - River Conservation Directory: NYS Dept. of Environmental Conservation, 1981 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Safe Energy Movement, 1977-1985 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Save the Redwoods League, 1986 (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Save the River: St. Lawrence River, 1982-1985; Undated (Box 6 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Section 208 -- League of Women Voters Updates, 1976-1977 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - "Setting the Course for Clean Water" -- National Wildlife Federation, 1977 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Shorewalkers, 1984-1986; Undated (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Social Action Center --Notes Newsletter, 1984 January-1984 May (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Status Report on Hazardous Waste Litigation -- Environmental Protection Bureau, ca. 1985 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Summary of Hudson River PCB Study Results, 1978 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Tank Bulletin: NYS Dept. of Environmental Conservation, 1991 Fall (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Total Access Troy: Channel 16, 1979; Undated (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Toxic Substances: Citizen Guides, 1980-1981 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Transportation Along the Hudson, 1978; 1980; Undated (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Transportation -- Railroad Brochures, 1981 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Tri-State Regional Planning Commission: Annual Regional Report, 1974 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Tri-State Regional Planning Commission: Economics of Energy, 1974 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Tri-State Regional Planning Commission: Outdoor Recreation in a Crowded Region, 1973 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Tri-State Regional Planning Commission: Partnership for Waste Management, 1973 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Tri-State Regional Planning Commission: Plan & Program for Regional Transportation through 2000, 1975-1976 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Tri-State Regional Planning Commission: Publications and Staff Reports, 1976 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Tri-State Regional Planning Commission: Regional Transit 1990 (revised and updated), 1974 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Tri-State Regional Planning Commission: Tri-State Coastal Zone Management Perspectives, 1975 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Tri-State Transportation Commission: Managing the Natural Environment, 1970 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Troy Bicentennial Engagement Calendar, 1976 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - The Tug Hill Region: Preparing for the Future (Commission Report), 1976 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Urban Cultural Parks Program, 1991-1992 (Box 7 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Walk Across America for Mother Earth, 1992 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - "Water and Related Land Resources of the Hudson River Basin", 1979 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Water Resources Data: New York, U.S. Geological Survey (NY 86-1), 1986 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)